KAREEM HOSNY

(+20)1013800529 Kareem.hosny2001@gmail.com

Junior .NET Software Engineer. I've gained experience in both software development and applied problem-solving. I worked as a Junior Full Stack Developer at Leader Group, where I contributed to building web applications and gained valuable experience in real-world software engineering. Furthermore, I participated twice in the Helwan-ICPC, which greatly improved my algorithmic thinking and ability to solve complex problems under pressure.

WORK EXPERIENCE

01/07/2023 TO 15/12/2023 JUNIOR FULLSTACK LEADER GROUP

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

01/01/2020 TO 01/01/2022

MONITOR
ICPC COMMUNITY (HELWAN UNI.)

VOLUNTEER AT BEDAYA FOR CHARITY WORK.

EDUCATION

FACULTY OF COMPUTER AND ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE - HELWAN UNIVERSITY 09/2019 TO 06/2023

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and IS, Major in Computer Science GPA: 3.78 / 4.0

TECHNICAL SKILLS

• C, C++

Python, Scikit-learn, Keras

• ASP.NET, .NET Core, Angular

C#, Java

• OOP, SOLID Principles

MySQL, Docker

HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Microsoft Office

SOFT SKILLS

- Problem Solving
- Adept at handling ambiguous problems as well as ability to think abstractly.
- Creative Thinking
- Fast Learner
- Decision Making

COLLEGE PROJECTS

- Object Detection project using YOLOv4.
- "Bug Tracking System" Desktop Application with Java.
- SVM and ANN Implementation using numerical/image datasets.
- N-Queen game using 2 Algorithms (Differential evolution & Backtracking) in addition to visual comparison between the two (+GUI).
- Thread-based N-Queen Solver using Java (+ GUI).
- process manager using linux Terminal Commands' (implemented with C).
- Front-End for a Restaurant website using html, Css, JavaScript and Jquery.
- Back-End & Front-End for a social media website similar to instagram.
- Hotel Management Project with Java.
- 2D game designed from scratch with Unity.
- 3D game designed from scratch with Unity3D
- Application to use Graphics Algorithms to draw using GUI
- Lyrics Classification using NLP

CERIFICATIONS

- Certificate of achievement of the "Three Hundred and Fourty Third" place in 2020
 ACPC kickoff online individual contest
- Certificate of achievement of the "Twenty First" place in 2020 Helwan University collegiate programming contest AAST
- Certificate of Completion "The Complete Python 3 Course : Go from Beginner to Advanced" online course from Udemy in 2018
- Certificate of Completion "30 Days of Python" online course from Udemy in 2019
- Certificate of Completion "Learn MySQL For Beginners " Online Course from Udemy in 2021
- Certificate of Completion "Java Programming : Complete Beginner to Advanced"
 Online Course from Udemy in 2021
- Certificate of Completion "Data structures with C Programming in Arabic" Online Course from Udemy in 2021
- Certificate of Completion " Supervised Machine Learning: Regression and Classification" Online Course from Coursera in 2022 by Andrew NG

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Military Status : Completed
 To Complete

• IELTS (overall) score: 7.5